<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Network Analysis on Sven De Maeyer</title>
    <link>/tags/social-network-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Network Analysis on Sven De Maeyer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/social-network-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/potential-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/potential-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.potentialproject.be/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools and teachers around the world are facing a growing diversity and increasing complexity in the classroom (Banks et al., 2007). In the past, pupils’ assignments to classrooms and schools have often fostered segregation rather than encouraged inclusion. Today, we see a tendency towards more inclusive learning environments (cf. amongst others, the UN Convention of 2006, ratified by Belgium in 2009). However, this poses challenges to the professional development of (pre-service) teachers and teams. Consequently, the main objective of the project ‘POTENTIAL - Power to Teach All’, is to develop the competences of (pre-service) teachers and school teams to create inclusive learning environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spectrum of competences to create inclusive learning environments, two major objectives are distinguished:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(A) appreciating and exploiting diversity in the classroom;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applying an intersectional perspective to education, reveals the fact that diversity is an inherent part of every classroom (Van Avermaet &amp;amp; Sierens, 2010). That is, every classroom consists of a diverse group of students, with regard to such characteristics as gender, age, socio-economic position, language, sexual orientation, religious beliefs, (dis)abilities, ethnic and cultural  background, … In order for teachers to create maximal learning opportunities for each student, certain skills and attitudes are necessary. First, in order to create a positive classroom environment, teacher attitudes should be appreciative, considering the diversity present not as a barrier to teaching and learning, but as an opportunity. Second, didactical skills and knowhow to create a learning environment suited to the needs of every student, are crucial in creating inclusive learning environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(B) realizing collaborative teaming in the school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating inclusive learning environments assumes that no individual or isolated teacher can expect to have all the knowledge required to meet the needs of all students in the classroom. Equitable learning environments require support for all different participants and a shared responsibility towards these participants (Killorana et al., 2014). Therefore, competences to realize collaborative teaming are necessary in order to successfully create inclusive learning environments (Hunt et al., 2003).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
