<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Video-learning on Sven De Maeyer</title>
    <link>/tags/video-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video-learning on Sven De Maeyer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/video-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/bofmarijn-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bofmarijn-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research project aims to understand the process of how students differ in watching online instructional videos in a flipped classroom and how different strategies of processing these videos before attending the classroom are related to differences in student in-classroom behavior and student academic performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three research questions are put forward:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RQ1: Can we detect patterns in students watching behavior while learning from instructional videos that are indicative of the learning strategies students use to cognitively process the information in these videos?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RQ2: How are differences in students processing strategies while learning from instructional videos in a flipped classroom related to differences in students&amp;rsquo; in-classroom learning behavior?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RQ3: How are differences in students processing strategies while learning from instructional videos in a flipped classroom related to differences in student academic performance?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research question one will be investigated in a lab study in which 90 students in social sciences will participate. Research questions two and three will be investigated in a field study in a statistics course in the faculty of social sciences. Both the lab study and the field study will combine trace data with qualitative data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
