<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tine Mombaers on Sven De Maeyer</title>
    <link>/authors/tine-mombaers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tine Mombaers on Sven De Maeyer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/tine-mombaers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/fwo_tine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/fwo_tine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-by-comparison-an-effective-instruction-method-for-better-writing-education&#34;&gt;Learning by comparison: an effective instruction method for better writing education&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing well is an important competence to be successful in higher education and in the labor market. That is why learning to write occupies a prominent place in the Dutch profession. This research project aims to develop instructional design principles that help students learn to write better texts. Earlier writing instruction research shows that students need conceptual knowledge about text quality. How this knowledge develops, however, has hardly been researched. In other areas such as physics and problem-solving, on the other hand, it has been shown that comparing examples helps. But to what extent do these insights also apply to writing instruction? What exactly does this learning process look like? Does it lead to pupils writing better texts and under what conditions? Although previous research suggests that comparing texts can be a promising method of instruction, these principles have hardly been researched in the context of writing instruction. This research will lead to answers to the above questions. By carrying out a quasi-experimental data collection in an authentic school context, this research also leads to a scientifically proven instruction method that can make secondary school students better writers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
