<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Sven De Maeyer</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Sven De Maeyer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/dpac-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/dpac-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.d-pac.be/english/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Digital Platform for the Assessment of Competences (D-Pac) is an innovative tool for assessing a wide range of competences, based on the method of Comparative Judgement. It can be used within a variety of contexts (e.g., for writing ability, self-reflection, and problem-solving) and for different purposes (e.g., for formative evaluation, peer assessment, research, selection, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparative Judgement  is based on Thurstone’s Law of Comparative Judgement. This law stipulates that people are better and more reliable in comparing two things than in assigning an absolute score to (only) one thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D-PAC was a four year IWT-SBO funded research project. Project partners were University of Antwerp,
Ghent University and iMinds (now: imec). During this project, the merits of comparative judgement
for the assessment of competencies were investigated. Research provided detailed insights into the
reliability, validity and efficiency of the method. Moreover, feedback opportunities towards assessees
and organisations were explored. In total, the award-winning D-PAC project will result in four doctoral
dissertations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/lift-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/lift-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://liftwritingresearch.com/english/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;LIFT project&lt;/strong&gt; (Improving pre-university students’ performance in academic synthesis tasks with Level up Instructions and Feedback tool) is an NWO-funded project in which we study text quality and writing processes of syntheiss texts. The aim of the study is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Map the development of text quality, writing processes and writer characteristics over the grades (Grade 10-11-12),
Investigate the link between different aspects of the writing process and the quality of the synthesis text (and the relation to personal writer characteristics),
Develop feedback on the both the product (text quality) and the writing process of synthesis texts (and to test its effect),
Develop instruction to improve synthesis writing (and to test its effect).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/valies-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/valies-project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edo-valies.be/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We zetten binnen VALIES sterk in op onderzoek dat zal bijdragen aan het ontwikkelen van effectieve EDO praktijken in scholen. Daartoe hebben we vijf onderzoekslijnen. Elk van de vijf doctoraatstudenten stelt haar of zijn lijn hier kort voor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lijn-1-het-grote-edo-doel-actiecompetentie&#34;&gt;Lijn 1 – Het grote EDO doel : actiecompetentie&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onderzoekster : Wanda Sass&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In deze onderzoekslijn wordt het begrip actiecompetentie verder onderzocht. We zien actiecompetentie als het geheel van drie onderdelen: (1) de wil om een actief engagement aan te gaan voor duurzaamheid, (2) kennis van (eigen) actiemogelijkheden, en (3) het vertrouwen in de eigen kunde om actie te ondernemen. Ik werk hiervoor een vernieuw conceptueel kader uit en ook diverse meetinstrumenten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lijn-2-professionele-ontwikkeling-van-schoolteams&#34;&gt;Lijn 2 – Professionele ontwikkeling van schoolteams&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onderzoekster : Kirsten Bonte&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;De onderzoekslijn brengt het EDO professionaliseringstraject van leerkrachten in kaart. We onderzoeken hoe de persoonlijke overtuigingen van leerkrachten m.b.t.  leergemeenschap van invloed zijn op hun leergedragingen. Ook gaan we na wat de effecten zijn van het professionaliseringstraject op de EDO competenties van leerkrachten en op het EDO materiaal dat ze ontwerpen om te gebruiken in de klas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lijn-3-effecten-van-edo-op-leerlingen&#34;&gt;Lijn 3 – Effecten van EDO op leerlingen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onderzoekster : Eleni Sinakou&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In deze onderzoekslijn verkennen we de effecten van het EDO professionaliseringstraject op leerkrachten en op leerlingen. Het traject heeft als doel om de leraren te ondersteunen in het opzetten van onderwijsarrangementen in het kader voor Educatie voor Duurzame Ontwikkeling. We bestuderen ook of en hoe deze praktijken bij kunnen dragen aan de actiecompetentie van leerlingen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lijn-4-edo-schoolcultuur-en-beleid&#34;&gt;Lijn 4 – EDO schoolcultuur en –beleid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onderzoeker : Dries Verhelst&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geen twee scholen zijn dezelfde, en het binnenbrengen van innovaties (zoals Educatie voor Duurzame Ontwikkeling) in het onderwijs hangt sterk samen met de aard van de school. In deze onderzoekslijn bestuderen we de schoolcultuur en de schoolse beleidsvoering rond EDO. Ook de impact van cultuur en beleid op het al dan niet succesvol implementeren van EDO hoort daarbij.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lijn-5-edo-buiten-de-schoolmuren&#34;&gt;Lijn 5 – EDO buiten de schoolmuren&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onderzoek(st)er : De aanwerving loopt 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kinderen brengen een belangrijk deel van hun tijd door op school. Ze brengen echter ook een belangrijk deel van hun tijd niet op school door. Deze onderzoekslijn wil vat krijgen op het samenspel tussen de thuissituatie en de schoolse context als het aankomt op de duurzaamheidsattitudes van leerlingen. Daarnaast verkennen we ook of en in welke mate EDO op school via de leerlingen kan doorsijpelen tot in het gezin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/potential-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/potential-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.potentialproject.be/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools and teachers around the world are facing a growing diversity and increasing complexity in the classroom (Banks et al., 2007). In the past, pupils’ assignments to classrooms and schools have often fostered segregation rather than encouraged inclusion. Today, we see a tendency towards more inclusive learning environments (cf. amongst others, the UN Convention of 2006, ratified by Belgium in 2009). However, this poses challenges to the professional development of (pre-service) teachers and teams. Consequently, the main objective of the project ‘POTENTIAL - Power to Teach All’, is to develop the competences of (pre-service) teachers and school teams to create inclusive learning environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spectrum of competences to create inclusive learning environments, two major objectives are distinguished:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(A) appreciating and exploiting diversity in the classroom;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applying an intersectional perspective to education, reveals the fact that diversity is an inherent part of every classroom (Van Avermaet &amp;amp; Sierens, 2010). That is, every classroom consists of a diverse group of students, with regard to such characteristics as gender, age, socio-economic position, language, sexual orientation, religious beliefs, (dis)abilities, ethnic and cultural  background, … In order for teachers to create maximal learning opportunities for each student, certain skills and attitudes are necessary. First, in order to create a positive classroom environment, teacher attitudes should be appreciative, considering the diversity present not as a barrier to teaching and learning, but as an opportunity. Second, didactical skills and knowhow to create a learning environment suited to the needs of every student, are crucial in creating inclusive learning environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(B) realizing collaborative teaming in the school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating inclusive learning environments assumes that no individual or isolated teacher can expect to have all the knowledge required to meet the needs of all students in the classroom. Equitable learning environments require support for all different participants and a shared responsibility towards these participants (Killorana et al., 2014). Therefore, competences to realize collaborative teaming are necessary in order to successfully create inclusive learning environments (Hunt et al., 2003).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/timss-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/timss-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uantwerpen.be/nl/projecten/timss-2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Flanders TIMSS 2019 is executed by research group EduBROn and research Centre Quest at the Arteveldehogeschool. This research project is commissioned by the Dept. of Education and Training of the Flemish Government.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
