<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Sven De Maeyer</title>
    <link>/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Sven De Maeyer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling eye-tracking data in comparative judgement</title>
      <link>/talk/2020-11-24-earl-sig27-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2020-11-24-earl-sig27-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If we use the eye tracker to register eye movements while assessors compare two texts in Comparative Judgement, we are confronted with the question of how to model the resulting data statistically. In this presentation we talk more specifically about the modeling of &amp;lsquo;Gaze event durations&amp;rsquo;. We demonstrate the added value of a &lt;em&gt;finite mixture model&lt;/em&gt; and present the results of analyses using bayesian estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the presentation we present different statistical models that can be the basis of the resulting data. In the finite mixture models we start from potentially 2 cognitive processes which determine how long assessors look during a visit to an AOI (in this case an AOI is equal to one of the two texts they look at): one process we call &amp;lsquo;scanning&amp;rsquo; for the time being (short registered times in one of the two texts to quickly form an image of the text), the other process we call &amp;lsquo;reading for text comprehension&amp;rsquo; (longer registered times in one of the two texts where the text is read systematically).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Bayesian analysis with R</title>
      <link>/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of research relies on statistical analyses that are in general grounded within Null-Hypothesis Significance Testing (NHST). But NHST has it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;downsides&amp;rsquo;. First of all, NHST tests a &amp;lsquo;null-hypothesis&amp;rsquo; rather than the real research hypothesis we&amp;rsquo;re interested in. And secondly, NHST makes use of &lt;em&gt;imaginary&lt;/em&gt; samples (the sampling distribution). Finally, NHST doesn&amp;rsquo;t quantify the uncertianty of parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The framework of Bayesian analysis is a tool that can overcome these flaws of NHST. In this talk I introduced the basic idea of Bayesian analysis, the way Markov Chain Monte Carlo works (conceptually) and how to implement it in R making use of the &lt;code&gt;brms&lt;/code&gt; package to compile code for Stan (an mcmc sampler in C++). The talk is a gentle introduction (in Dutch).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
